<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
 <title type="text">Hanglip Associates Blog: Hanglip Associates Blog</title>
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.hanglip.org/feeds\all.atom.xml" />
 <link href="http://www.hanglip.org/index.html" />
 <id>urn:http-www-hanglip-org:-index-html</id>
 <updated>2020-04-28T10:36:01Z</updated>
 <entry>
  <title type="text">Level 4 ahoy!</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.hanglip.org/2020\04\level-4-ahoy.html?utm_source=all&amp;utm_medium=Atom" />
  <id>urn:http-www-hanglip-org:-2020-04-level-4-ahoy-html</id>
  <published>2020-04-28T10:36:01Z</published>
  <updated>2020-04-28T10:36:01Z</updated>
  <author>
   <name>SM Osler</name></author>
  <content type="html">
&lt;blockquote&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;It appears Hanglip will return to business as usual in a few days. Wool sales will presumably go ahead, travel will be eased, though we can&amp;rsquo;t yet expect to reach Bloemfontein (no inter province travel). Hey, de Aar, here we come &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We are closer and closer to some of our Old Land regeneration projects, wanting to clear and plant by latest October.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.hanglip.org/2020\04\level-4-ahoy.html?utm_source=all&amp;amp;utm_medium=Atom"&gt;&lt;em&gt;More&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content></entry>
 <entry>
  <title type="text">HCET Lockdown</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.hanglip.org/2020\04\hcet-lockdown.html?utm_source=all&amp;utm_medium=Atom" />
  <id>urn:http-www-hanglip-org:-2020-04-hcet-lockdown-html</id>
  <published>2020-04-08T07:44:22Z</published>
  <updated>2020-04-08T07:44:22Z</updated>
  <author>
   <name>SM Osler</name></author>
  <content type="html">
&lt;h1 id="the-hantam-community-education-trust-lockdown-report-as-at-6-april-2020"&gt;The Hantam Community Education Trust Lockdown report as at 6 April 2020&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do indeed find ourselves in extraordinary and stressful times. There is so much uncertainty, especially if the lockdown is extended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How are we facing the challenges that this imposes on the work of the trust and all its beneficiaries:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The school, ECD and Effective Parenting Programme are all on lockdown. This is very worrying for us as our children are not able to work online, should the lockdown be prolonged the challenge of catching up is even greater. It is extremely challenging for many of the students to work from homes where parents are not literate. Where we are able, we have encouraged farms and older literate siblings to play a supportive role, concentrating only on Maths and English. Our library is accessible on Wednesday mornings, (when the clinic is open) books can be taken out by the parents and children. Our greatest concern is for the children who attend the Trust school from town. The reality is when schools re-open, many of the town parents will be unable to pay for their children’s transport; our fear is that these children could well drop out of school.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.hanglip.org/2020\04\hcet-lockdown.html?utm_source=all&amp;amp;utm_medium=Atom"&gt;&lt;em&gt;More&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content></entry>
 <entry>
  <title type="text">Lockdown Lessons</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.hanglip.org/2020\04\lockdown-lessons.html?utm_source=all&amp;utm_medium=Atom" />
  <id>urn:http-www-hanglip-org:-2020-04-lockdown-lessons-html</id>
  <published>2020-04-03T10:35:00Z</published>
  <updated>2020-04-03T10:35:00Z</updated>
  <author>
   <name>SM Osler</name></author>
  <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;The Skuur (Shearing Shed) has always doubled as a culture and learning centre. During Lockdown, we cobbled up a few computers to enable some learners from the staff hamlet to socialise online, and to hone their English and Algebra skills.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.hanglip.org/2020\04\lockdown-lessons.html?utm_source=all&amp;amp;utm_medium=Atom"&gt;&lt;em&gt;More&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content></entry>
 <entry>
  <title type="text">WI WI</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.hanglip.org/2020\03\wi-wi.html?utm_source=all&amp;utm_medium=Atom" />
  <id>urn:http-www-hanglip-org:-2020-03-wi-wi-html</id>
  <published>2020-03-29T16:58:46Z</published>
  <updated>2020-03-29T16:58:46Z</updated>
  <author>
   <name>SM Osler</name></author>
  <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;We apply the term &amp;lsquo;WI WI&amp;rsquo; to the ideas bounced around on the stoep, in vehicles, anywhere we get a moment to address the wonders of the world, and especially of the farming world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a while, we called it &lt;strong&gt;WIskunde&lt;/strong&gt;, then &lt;strong&gt;WIld Idea Society&lt;/strong&gt;, but the essential point is that WI stands for &amp;rsquo;&lt;strong&gt;W&lt;/strong&gt;ild &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;deas&amp;rsquo;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is there to life, if we can&amp;rsquo;t bandy about a few ideas, toss a melt of old world and new tech into the mix?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.hanglip.org/2020\03\wi-wi.html?utm_source=all&amp;amp;utm_medium=Atom"&gt;&lt;em&gt;More&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content></entry>
 <entry>
  <title type="text">Hanglip Associates</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.hanglip.org/2020\03\hanglip-associates.html?utm_source=all&amp;utm_medium=Atom" />
  <id>urn:http-www-hanglip-org:-2020-03-hanglip-associates-html</id>
  <published>2020-03-27T15:30:51Z</published>
  <updated>2020-03-27T15:30:51Z</updated>
  <author>
   <name>SM Osler</name></author>
  <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;These online pages serve to acquaint our Associates (especially during COVID&amp;ndash;19 Lockdown as at the time of writing) with developments on the farm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We added a page assessing our progress in terms of the UN Sustainable Development Goals. See &lt;strong&gt;SDG&lt;/strong&gt; on the Navigation Tab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are mulling over plans to regenerate worked out old crop lands (though no-one would believe, after our good rains, how sombre these lands looked only a month ago). Plans vary from job creation to soil and plant regeneration, involving both planting and small livestock.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.hanglip.org/2020\03\hanglip-associates.html?utm_source=all&amp;amp;utm_medium=Atom"&gt;&lt;em&gt;More&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content></entry></feed>