<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
 <title type="text">Hanglip Associates Blog: Posts tagged 'Working Words'</title>
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.hanglip.org/feeds\Working-Words.atom.xml" />
 <link href="http://www.hanglip.org/tags\Working-Words.html" />
 <id>urn:http-www-hanglip-org:-tags-Working-Words-html</id>
 <updated>2020-05-25T12:41:58Z</updated>
 <entry>
  <title type="text">Work Semantics</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.hanglip.org/2020\05\work-semantics.html?utm_source=Working-Words&amp;utm_medium=Atom" />
  <id>urn:http-www-hanglip-org:-2020-05-work-semantics-html</id>
  <published>2020-05-25T12:41:58Z</published>
  <updated>2020-05-25T12:41:58Z</updated>
  <author>
   <name>SM Osler</name></author>
  <content type="html">
&lt;h1 id="do-or-give-worker-semantics"&gt;DO or GIVE: &amp;ldquo;WORKER&amp;rdquo; SEMANTICS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We get our word &amp;ldquo;do&amp;rdquo; from Latin. I was taught that it meant &amp;ldquo;give&amp;rdquo; - as in &lt;strong&gt;DO&lt;/strong&gt;nate, whereas it has strayed through centuries in English to mean the opposite of idleness. I prefer to think of it as meaning both &amp;ldquo;do&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;give&amp;rdquo;. When I work for somebody, it feels better to know I am &amp;ldquo;giving&amp;rdquo; my employer something, rather than merely killing time. Just as surely, when idle, I can&amp;rsquo;t be giving at all. That said, idleness has its place. Bertrand Russell wrote &lt;strong&gt;In Praise of Idleness&lt;/strong&gt;, though I don&amp;rsquo;t recall him advocating a salary for idlers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same way, the words that came into our language courtesy of the Industrial Revolution are growing boring tiring. Take &amp;ldquo;manager&amp;rdquo;. The root is also from Latin: &amp;ldquo;manus&amp;rdquo; is a hand, and I suppose we must believe that managers &amp;ldquo;handle&amp;rdquo; things. In my mind, they &amp;ldquo;manipulate&amp;rdquo; rather than handle! Their task became to wheedle ever more work out of people, calling this &amp;ldquo;productivity&amp;rdquo;. If ever a word needed to be &amp;ldquo;decolonialised&amp;rdquo; it is that one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a long time, managers came from the ranks - they had proved themselves on the job. That ddn&amp;rsquo;t always make them good managers (see Dr Laurence J Peter, &lt;strong&gt;The Peter Principle&lt;/strong&gt;). However, back then, they were more effective than now in one sense: they were not asking others to do something they themselves could not do. Some respect naturally followed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When managers were no longer expected to perform what they expected from others, but rather &amp;ldquo;specialise&amp;rdquo; in management, respect was lost and it all began to unravel. It is difficult to respect someone who can&amp;rsquo;t do what s/he is asking you to do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.hanglip.org/2020\05\work-semantics.html?utm_source=Working-Words&amp;amp;utm_medium=Atom"&gt;&lt;em&gt;More&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content></entry></feed>